HAO JIANZONG (Jakehao)

- · haojianzong@gmail.com
- http://www.haojianzong.com
- · Shenzhen, China
- Mobile: (86)180-2865-8167

Summary

I am an iOS Developer with 3+ years experience, including exposure to web development both in front-end and backend.

I enjoy developing complex applications, both in user interface and system levels. I am currently working on QQMusic, the **NO.1 music App** in China. While developing for over **100 millions** users, I learn a lot about code optimization, debugging and writing reusable code.

As an iOS develop lead, I develop Klook iOS App, which is featured as "Best of 2015" by Apple.

Skills and Experience

iOS Development

iOS Software Architecture – I have good and board experience with iOS software architecture. I refactor several core UI components of QQMusic using MVC, making the code easy to understand and less error prone. In my experience, MVC is not the only option for iOS Apps. During the development of Klook iOS App, I apply MVVM to build the structure of the app. As a result, the code base of Klook iOS App is simple to develop, iterate, test, and maintain.

UI/Animation – I have rich experience in developing iOS user interface and animation. It is crucial for an iOS App to excel in UI/UX. Therefore, I work hard to achieve good UI/UX experience for every App I develop. I am skilled in using storyboard, Auto Layout and CAAnimation. Because using Interface Builder is not friendly to version control software, I prefer writing user interface code programmatically for complex UI components.

Web development

I am familiar with web development, both in **front-end and backend**. I have develop and maintain several commercial websites using jQuery, CSS and HTML. On the other hand, I have experience in Ruby on Rails development. Therefore, I am familiar with network programming, for example, http, json, tcp and Restful API.

Employment

Tencent Technology (Shenzhen) Co Ltd

iOS Software Engineer - August, 2015 - Present

- Skills used: iOS SDK, Objective-C, Instruments, TestFlight, Git Flow, Javascript
- Role overview: Architect and build important UI components for QQMusic iOS App. Build new features for the App. Refactor heritage code.
- Interesting challenges: Reduce the app size from 100M+ to 50M. Meanwhile, I refactor main UI component code. I also design a **cross-platform skin changing UI component** for the system, combining javascript and Objective-C techniques. As the app serves millions of users, we constantly collect feedback directly from users to improve App functions.

Klook Travel Technology Limited (klook.com)

iOS Software Engineer - Jul, 2014 - Aug, 2015

- · Skills used: iOS SDK, Test-Driven Development, TestFlight, Git Flow, Javascript, HTML, CSS, Java
- Role overview: Originally employed to build Klook iOS App from the ground up. I participate in every part of building the App, including UI design, Api service, testing, iterating and publishing. I also participate in the development of the web service, both frontend and backend.
- Interesting challenges: The App involved multi-language and multi-currency offshore payment. Complicated UI/Animation are built and tuned to make the App more appealing. The App is featured as Best New Apps by Apple on first launch. By the end of the year, it is featured as "Best of 2015" by Apple.

Guangzhou BestApp Co Ltd

iOS Software Engineer - Nov, 2013 - Jul, 2014

- · Skills used: iOS, Ruby on Rails, TDD, Git, Javascript, HTML, CSS
- Role overview: Develop a hotel booking iOS App. Involve in web front-end projects.

Education

2005 – 2009 Renmin University of China Bachelor, School of Business

2009 - 2012

Chinese Institute of Certified Public Accountants

Other

- Language Skills: Excellent in CET-6 and GMAT(730), proficient in speaking, reading and writing English.
- In my spare time, I read classic technology books, for example, Algorithms, Computer Systems and Programming Pearls.
- I host several repositories on Github such as JZDatepicker and some blog themes.
- I write about my career switch experience in Quora(http://qr.ae/GzYwd)